Matt Bordas

Computational Biologist bordasmatt@gmail.com • (714) 342-2575 • Linkedin • matthewbordas.com

PROFILE

Currently working as a computational biologist focused on using my experience as a software engineer to analyze, model, and understand -omics data. I have a bachelor's in computer science and four years of industry experience in full stack software engineering at a startup I co-founded. I've worked with a myriad of technologies, obtaining proficiencies in Python, Pandas, Flask, ReactJS, NodeJS, DevOps, data analysis, cloud computing, and cloud architecture. I am seeking a role in bioinformatics that will further progress my skills and broaden my exposure to various facets and problem areas within the field.

EXPERIENCE

Amaral Lab, Northwestern University

Evanston, IL (remote)

Visiting Scholar, Computational Biology

Sept 2020 - Present

Python, Pandas, Flask, Jupyter, ReactJS, Docker, AWS

- Conducts research projects at the <u>Amaral Lab</u> that fuse software, biology, and data science to understand and solve problems around aging
- Compiles and analyzes aging-related gene data from the National Center for Biotechnology Information (NCBI) to develop interactive web applications
- Applies machine learning methods from research paper (Nat Genet 47, 856–860 (2015)) to construct a predictive model that would preemptively score the effectiveness, worthiness, and potential impact of new aging research

Time by Ping

San Francisco, CA May 2016 - Mar 2020

Co-Founder, Lead Engineer

NodeJS, Docker, DevOps, AWS, MySQL, MongoDB, .NET, C#, Agile, TDD

- Co-founded <u>Time by Ping</u> during undergrad and developed the first version of an automated timekeeping product for lawyers and law firms
- Managed all engineering personnel and expanded the team from two to twelve people
- Led the engineering team through the company's first three fundraising rounds totaling over \$16 million

Lead Full Stack Engineer

June 2019 - Mar 2020

- Facilitated the project management, automation, and development of a detailed technical pipeline for onboarding new customers to the platform
- Spearheaded the creation of a new engineering team focused on DevOps, SRE, new customer onboarding, and onsite support
- Worked with the CEO and leadership to restructure the engineering team post-series A fundraising

Head of Engineering

Jan 2018 - June 2019

- Directed the engineering team to a successful series A fundraising round
- Oversaw the development, testing, and release of the product to the company's first users
- Provided on-call and on-site support for all users across the U.S. and U.K.

Software Engineer

May 2016 - Jan 2018

- Hired interns and developed a prototype that secured the first customer contract
- · Built and programmed the entire product from the ground up in coordination with the engineering co-founder
- Co-founded the company and collaborated with the founding team to outline the product requirements

COMMUNITY

Code2040

Mentor/Coach

San Francisco, CA

2019 - Present

- Serves as a volunteer for <u>Code2040</u>, a non-profit focused on improving the lack of representation of women and people of color in the technology industry
- Supervises mentors and provides recommendations on how to best support and provide resources for their mentees
- Coordinates recurring check-ins and organizes group wide events

EDUCATION

University of California, Davis

Davis, CA 2012 - 2016